日本語字幕仕上げ：光川  光荣字幕组（www.koeigame.cn）
Osaka's captain, Hirata, intercepts again!
おっと大阪
またもここで ひらがキャプテン平賀が　インターセプト
Hauer, Katayama, Hatake, Kubota.
ハウアー　片山　畑　窪田　４人のフォワードが　ゴールを狙っている
The four forwards are gunning for the goal.
This is Osaka Gunner's ultra attacking line-up they pride themselves in!
これぞ大阪ガンナーズの誇る超攻撃的布陣！
Here, here!
こっちや　こっち！
Hurry up and pass it here!
早よ　よこせ！
Uh...
えっと…
Got it!
もらい
Clear it, clear it!
クリアークリアー！
Uhh...
えっと…
Kubo, here!
来い　クボ！
GOAL!
ゴール！
Hatake scores to put Osaka 4 up!
決めたのは畑　大阪４点目！
And it's only been 40 minutes!
どとうまだ前半４０分
Osaka's relentless assault has given Kofu a huge mountain to climb.
大阪　怒濤の攻撃で甲府に大量リード！
"Might be"?
何とか　やれるって…自信あんのか？　あんた?
Are you confident?
Of course I am. Aren't you, Murakoshi?
そりゃあるよ　お前はねえの？　村越
What kind of player goes out on the field expecting to lose?
負けるつもりでピッチに立つ選手がいるかよ！
Isn't that right? Let's just sweep Osaka aside.
なら　関係ねえじゃん　ガツンと大阪　やっつけようぜ
Plus, I'm interested in how ETU will handle them.
ETU? There's no one from there that's representing the nation, right?
I'm looking forward to it.
楽しみだなぁ
What kind of football will you show me, Monsieur Tatsumi?
どんなフットボール見せてくれるんだろう…ムッシュ　タツミ
United we stand,Fly a flag 風を受け止めて
United we stand, Fly a flag!
kaze o uketomete
風を受け止めて
Let the wind blow through you
United we stand, Fly a flag!
United we stand,Fly a flag たなびけ勝利のflag
tanabike shouri no flag
たなびけ勝利の flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
haruka na gooru o shinjite
遥かなゴールを信じて
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けていて
hashiri tsuzuketeke
走り続けてけ
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ降り注げ光よ
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
汗は裏切らないって唇噛み締め
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め
何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
何度も立ち上がり大地を駆け抜ける
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
For the right! Hold on tight!
for the right
hold on tight
My story...
my story…
forever
Forever...
はい　以上です
Right, and that is all. Did everybody get it?
みんな　分かりましたか？
質問ある人
Any questions?
What? That's all?
ええっ！それだけですか
ほ…　本気かよこいつ
Is this guy for real?
Huh? No comments?
あれ？反応ないぞ
Bravo! I think it's fabulous, Tatsumi.
Bravo（ブラボ）
僕は　すばらしいと思ったよ　タッツミ
You sound sarcastic.
お前は　何か　うさんくさい
Uhh, to be honest...
いや　あのよ…
Your plan sounds kinda fun,
おもしれあんたの作戦は面白えんだけどよ
but will things be that smooth-sailing?
そんなに　うまくいくもんか？
Osaka won by 8 goals yesterday,
大阪は昨日８点取って勝ってんだぜ
while we were defeated in our previous game.
それに引き換え
おれ俺らは前の試合　落としてるしよ
What's the matter, Kuro? Are you lacking confidence?
どうしたの　クロちゃん
自信ねえか？
No, I have plenty!
Whether the plan succeeds or not is all up to you.
うまくいくも　いかねえもお前らしだいだけどね
I came up with this plan because I believe it will work.
うまくいくと思ってっから俺は
この作戦を立てたんだ
Though Osaka have four forwards,
大阪が４人フォワードいるっていってもよ
we have four defenders.
ウチだって　ディフェンスは　４バックで臨むんだ
They don't have a numerical advantage.
数じゃ負けてねえぜ
数より能力の差が問題だと思うんスけど
I feel that the difference in quality is the main problem rather than quantity.
Akasaki!
赤崎！
Kuro identified the key to this just now; which is that my plan is fun.
さっき　クロが　いい事言ったよ
俺の作戦　面白いってね
That's the important part.
大事なのは　そこだ
The question is whether or not you can enjoy yourselves in this game.
お前らがこの試合を面白がれるかどうか
If you carry out my instructions, this game...
俺の作戦どおりいったら
この試合
will be one hell of a ride.
そりゃ面白いものになる
If there were to be a thrilling match, the fans will get excited well.
面白い試合になれば観客も盛り上がる
This will allow you to enjoy yourselves even more.
お前たちも余計楽しくプレーできる
そういう時だよ
That's the time when you can play better than you've ever imagined.
自分の想像を超えた　いいプレーができちまうって時は
And as a result,
そんで結果的に
we will be the first to clean up the undefeated Osaka team.
今期負けなしの大阪を俺たちが初めて　やっつけるんだ
See, doesn't that sound fun?
ほら　面白い事ずくめだろ？
うし！　いいね
Alright, ready?
Well, in order to do that, you will have to drill whatever I will be telling you into your heads.
じゃ　そのために
これから　こいつを頭と体に　たたき込んでもらう
Let's start!
始めっぞ
Ok!
ウッス！
Alright, let's destroy Osaka!
よし！大阪　たたきつぶすぞ！
Don't forget your roles!
自分の役割　忘れるな
Let's do it.
頼むぞ
Baki, you'll just have to keep chasing after the ball as always.
バッキは　いつものようにボールを気力で追いかけてくれればいいから
Understood.
ウス！
10th League Match
ETU vs Osaka Gunners
Thank you.
ありがとうございました
Wow, it's pizza!
ワーイ　ピザだ！
今日も頼むぜ！
ＥＴＵに負けるな！
The forwards: Katayama, followed by Hatake.
フォワードの片山
同じく畑
The defender: Biva.
ディフェンスのリマー
I guess being undefeated brings confidence as they're all looking strong.
やっぱり連勝してるだけあって
みんな　いい顔してるな
The Japanese internationals: Shimura, Hiraga, and Terauchi.
おっと　日本代表の志村…
平賀…　寺内
そして　フル代表と五輪代表兼任のこむろ若手有望株　小室や
And the young wonderkid, Komuro, who's both a national and Olympic player.
Though they're all defenders, Osaka still have four national players.
ディフェンシブな選手が多いとはいえ
代表が４人もいるとはねえ…
And ETU doesn't even have one...
それに引き換え
ＥＴＵはゼロだもんな
In addition,
更に　ここまで　リーグ最多得点その源
they have the league's top scorer.
Hauer, the Dutchman. With him around, their offense is devastating.
長身オランダ人の　ハウアーを
起点とする攻撃陣は
破壊力あるからなぁ
Osaka Gunner's latest addition among the 4 forwards: Kubota.
大阪ガンナーズ　４トップの
一番後ろに入る窪田
Since Dulfer became their manager, he's been a first team regular.
ダルファー監督が指揮するようになってから
レギュラーに定着した選手
When they shoot, it's awesome!
シュートの瞬間って最高！
It's so intense!
わっしょいって感じでさ
Alright, I'm pumped up for this!
よし　テンション上がってきた！
大阪倒すぞ！
Let's beat Osaka!
ETU! ETU! East Tokyo United!
ＥＴＵ！　ＥＴＵ！イースト　トーキョー　ユナイテッド！
Hey, join me! It's embarrassing to do it alone!
やれよ
１人で恥ずかしいじゃん
But Kota...
だって　コータ
today's match is a difficult one.
今日は　さすがに厳しいって
Osaka have four national players,
大阪は日本代表が４人もいるし
おまけに４トップとかいってスゲー攻撃してくんじゃん
and they have 4 forwards in their ultra attacking line-up.
Do you really think ETU's defense can shut them down?
ＥＴＵのディフェンス陣がさ
それ止められると思うか？コータ
確かに
That's true...
See?
だろ
…うわ?！見ろよ
Tetta, Yoshio! Look!
テッタ！　ヨシオ！
It's the national coach, Blanc!
ブランだ！代表監督のブランだ！
Blanc, Blanc!
ブラン！　ブラン！
Blanc?
ブラン？
ホンマかいな
Seriously?
Those cute kids are running this way. Should I give them my autograph?
N-no, you can't!
We're in a hurry and it'll cause a ruckus here!
Aww, they'll have a bad impression of me!
It'll be okay, please do it another time.
Blanc is going away.
うわ　行っちゃうよ　ブラン
Wait...
待って！
I'm sorry, kids. It's this evil guy's fault.
Hey Blanc! Stop using our players!
おいコラ　ブラン！
あんましウチの選手　代表に呼ばんといて！
チームの試合に支障出るやろ！
It'll hinder the team's performances!
ケガさしたら承知せえへんぞ！
You're in trouble if they get injured!
Are you listening, Blanc?!
聞いとんのか　ブラン！
こ…　怖い
Scary...
でも　あんな事　言えんのがちょっと　うらやましい
But I'm kinda jealous that they can say something like that.
Hey, since Blanc is watching today...
ねえねえ　ブランが見に来てる　って事はさ…
Yeah?
If our players perform well today...
今日　ウチの選手が活躍とかしたらさあ…
That means...
ひょっとしたら…
ETU will have a national player?!
ＥＴＵから 日本代表選手
Hey, I'm all fired up!
何か急にワクワクしてきた
Let's cheer our hearts out!
やっぱりガツンと応援しようぜ
Let's beat Osaka!
大阪倒す！
That might be hard to achieve, but do your best, ETU!
…のは無理でも
頑張れＥＴＵ！
Yeah!
おう！
Yes, the candidates will be announced after the game, as usual.
当選者の発表はいつものように試合終了後に…
Hey, have you seen my coat?
ねえ
俺のジャケット知んない？
Nope.
え？　知らないよ
That's weird, where did I put it?
あれ？　どこ置いたっけ…
Where would you prefer to watch the match from?
試合はどちらで見られます？
Haven't see you in a while, Takeshi Tatsumi.
ハロ　ダルファ
Hello, Dulfer.
What're you doing, Monsieur Blanc?
監督同士が試合前から火花を散らしている
The two managers are exchanging sparks.
It might look like a friendly conversation, but they are trying to read each other.
何気ない会話でも
腹の中では相手の手の内を探ろうとしてるはず
So who'll take the initiative? The battle has already begun.
どちらがイニシアチブを取るのか
既に戦いは始まっている
So, Tatsumi, how confident are you about today's match?
どうですか　達海監督？
この試合に対する自信のほどは？
Well, let's just say I'm usually not one to lack confidence.
ま　なくはないような
そんな感じ
Oh, I see. I guess he doesn't want to elaborate on that.
ほう　深くは語らずといったところか
I can read that as a lack of confidence on his part.
取りようによっては自信のなさの
表れとも見えるが…
Then, do you mind if I ask a question?
じゃあ　俺から質問してもいい？
Dulfer, you're Dutch, right?
ダルファー　あんた　オランダ人だろ？
Is it true that in Holland...
オランダってさ…
there are more bikes than people?
人口より自転車の数が多いってホント？
What a random question. It seems that he's not under any pressure.
何という緊張感のないどうでもいい質問だ
And the atmosphere's supposed to be tense right before the match... What on earth is he thinking of?
この試合前のピリピリしたムードの中で
この男　一体何を考えてる
What did he say?
Something that's not worth translating.
Well, the game is about to start, so let's get a move-on.
まあ　試合開始も近いですから
立ち話はここら辺にしましょうか
うん　そうだね
I guess so.
Let's both do our best.
Alright, make sure to stretch properly.
よし　よし！
しっかり体　ほぐしとけ
夜は　まだまだ冷えるからな
The temperature's gonna drop at night. Do it right to avoid injuries.
ケガしないように　しっかりやれ
Alright! I have a premonition that it's going to be a Katayama day today.
おし！今日は体軽いわ
片山デーになる予感するなぁ
So Shimu, please pass the ball to me, and I'll smash it against the back of the net.
せやから　シムさん
俺にボール回してな
バッシバシ決めたるで
Hey, Kata!
コラ！　カタ！
今シーズンお前は３得点で　俺は４得点や
You've scored three goals so far, while I've scored four.
決定力は　俺のほうが上やぞ
My abilities are obviously better!
You understand right, Shimu?
分かるやろ　シムさん
俺にパスしたら　自分にアシストつくんやで
If you pass the ball to me, you'll get to increase your assists tally.
What are you babbling about?
何ぬかしとんねん　畑！
お前この前　俺が　アシストしてやったん 忘れたんか？
Have you forgotten about the time I assisted you?
何やねん　お前！
Hey, you're so cheap.
小さい男やな！
まあまあ　ケンカはやめよう２人とも
Relax, there's no need to quarrel.
Don't worry, I understand that both of you are doing your best in helping me to...
大丈夫
２人とも　俺の才能を伸ばそうと思ってくれてんのは
express my abilities.
俺　分かってるから
誰も　そんな話してへんちゅうに！
Nobody said anything like that!
Shimu never gets what anyone is saying.
相変わらず　話かみ合わんわ　シムさん
Yo, Hauer!
よう　ハウアー
Make sure to head the ball towards me, okay?
ポストプレーん時は俺のほうにボール転がしてな
What? You're worrying about your hair again?!
何や　お前？　また髪形気にしてんのか？
Didn't we mention that it looks crap on you and your big face?
にお似合うてへん言うとるやろが
ゴツイ顔して
なっ　何か伝わってしもた！
Crap, I think he understood what we were saying!
すまん！　ハウアー
I'm sorry, Hauer! I was just kidding, so please pass the ball to me.
ウソやで　ウソ！
せやからパスして
Our Kansai forwards are being loud again.
今日も　うるせえな
フォワードの関西コンビは
Those guys are always like that.
あいつらは　調子こいてるくらいが　ちょうどいいんスよ
それに比べて
On the other hand...
You're quiet as always, Kubota.
お前は　おとなしいくらいがちょうどいいのかもな 漥田
Oh, probably, yeah.
あ…　ああ　多分
はい
つまんねえ！
How boring!
You should say something more interesting.
お前は…　もうちょっとだけでも面白い事　言えよ
Oh, probably, yes.
ああ　多分　はい
Are you guys done with your warm-ups?
You guys ready for battle?
We've come to this stadium to win.
Oh, there you are, Tatsumi. I found your jacket.
達海さん　ジャケットあったよ！
Where you've been? We're running out of time!
もう　どこ行ってたのよ
この時間のないときに
うん　ダルファーと　しゃべってた
I had a little chat with Dulfer.
Man, he looks so confident.
いや　自信たっぷりって顔してたよ
Well, that's to be expected when you're in first place and also undefeated.
そりゃ　負けなしで首位走ってんだから　当然だけど
But it went well. I'm kinda relieved.
まあ　よかったよかったえ　ちょっと安心
It seems he'll be using his usual ultra attacking line-up.
あの様子なら
いつもの超攻撃的布陣で来てくれるよ
ETU is a team that bases their tactics on their opponent's playing style.
However, we will stick to our beautiful, offensive style...
and overwhelm ETU.
ETU is a team that bases their tactics on their opponent's playing style.
ＥＴＵは　相手によって戦術を変えてくるチーム
However, we will stick to our beautiful, offensive style and overwhelm ETU.
Beautiful and effective football.
美しく　たくましい　フットボール
我々は自分たちのスタイルに誇りを持ったチームだ
We are a team that takes pride in our own playing style.
いくら向こうがこそく姑息に勝利を狙ってこようと
No matter how much they try to improvise in order to win,
we will not change our principles.
我々は信念を曲げてはならない
The Osaka Gunners' line-up is as follows...
大阪ガンナーズリザーブメンバーは　ご覧のとおりです
ガンナ　ガンナ　大阪ガンナーズ！
Now, it's finally time.
さあ　お待たせしました
We will now announce the starting line-up of East Tokyo United.
我らがイースト　トーキョー　ユナイテッドスターティングメンバーの発表です
Number 1, goalkeeper: Midorikawa Hiroshi!
ひろし背番号１番ゴールキーパー　緑川　宏
Dori! Dori!
ドリ！　ドリ！
Number 2, defender: Kuroda Kazuki!
背番号２番ディフェンダー　黒田一樹
黒田！　黒田！
Kuroda! Kuroda!
Number 3, defender: Sugie Yusaku!
背番号３番ディフェンダー　杉江勇作
Sugie! Sugie!
杉江！ 杉江！
Number 16, defender: Kiyokawa Kazumi!
背番号１６番ディフェンダー　清川和巳
Kiyokawa! Kiyokawa!
清川！ 清川！
Number 22, defender...
背番号２２番ディフェンダー…石滨修
Their defensive line-up is the same as always.
ディフェンス陣は　いつもと同じ
石滨 石滨
I know they have some sort of plan...
何か策があるのは確実なんだけど…
Number 6, midfielder: Murakoshi Shigeyuki!
背番号６番ミッドフィールダー　村越茂幸
Alright!
うおっし！
We're counting on you, Mr. ETU!
頼むぜ　ミスターＥＴＵ
背番号７番ミッドフィールダー　椿　大介
Number 7, midfielder: Tsubaki Daisuke!
椿！ 椿！
Tsubaki! Tsubaki!
背番号１０番ミッドフィールダー　ルイジ吉田
Number 10, midfielder: Luigi Yoshida!
王子！　王子！
ワーオ！ジーノ！
Gino!
Prince!
Number 15, midfielder: Akasaki Ryo!
背番号１５番　ミッドフィールダー　赤崎　遼
Akasaki! Akasaki!
赤崎！ 赤崎！
Number 20, forward: Sera Kyohei!
背番号２０番　フォワード　世良恭平
Sera! Sera!
世良！ 世良！
世良だ！
It's Sera.
Huh? What about Tanba?
たんばあれ？　今日は丹波は？
Number 11, forward: Natsuki Yotaro!
背番号１１番フォワード　夏木陽太郎
What? Two forwards?!
夏木！ 夏木！
えっ　フォワード２枚た　達海のヤツ
T-Tatsumi,
are you really gonna go head-to-head offensively against Osaka?!
あの超攻撃的な大阪に対して
攻撃でやり合うつもりかよ！
そうきたか　ムッシュ　タツミ
So that's your plan, Monsieur Tatsumi.
And the manager: Tatsumi Takeshi!
そして監督は達海　猛！
Is this the reason why ETU's practices were not open to the public lately?
ここ２日　ＥＴＵの練習が非公開だった理由は
これ？
Can this line-up do something against Osaka's devastating offense?
この布陣で　大阪の猛攻に対抗できるわけ？
オー　オー　オー　俺たちの誇り
オー　オー　オー　赤と黒のイレブン
オー　オー　オー　イースト　トーキョー　ユナイテッド
ETU ETU ETU
They have firm expressions. The both of them.
いい顔してやがんじゃねえか
どっちの監督もよ
This match might prove to be quite interesting.
こいつはなかなか　見ごたえのある試合になるかもしんねえな
Alright, let's keep our voices up for the match!
よし　よし！
しっかり声出していくぞ！
Focus! If you let your guard down, they'll send us to the cleaners!
集中しろよ！
集中切らしたら一気にやられちまうぞ！
Side-backs, stick close to Katayama and Hatake.
片山と畑には　しつこくついていけよ
サイド２人！
う…　オス！
Yes!
Oh my, the defense is all pumped up.
いやいや　随分と　張り切ってるじゃないか　ディフェンス陣
それなら僕も今日は　頑張っちゃおうかな
Then I too, shall do my best just for today.
What's that "just for today" supposed to mean?
今日はって何スか?今日はって
Alright, I'm calm.
よし　落ち着いてるぞ　俺
やってやる！　やってやる！やってやる！
I'll show you! I'll show you! I'll show you!
き…　気合い入ってるな世良さん
Sera's fired up, but he looks kinda scary.
ちょっと怖いけど
それに比べてナツさんは
On the other hand, Natsu looks nervous.
何か気が張っているような…
Listen up, we did everything we could.
よし　いいか！
俺たちは　やる事はやった
Now we just have to show it on the pitch!
あとは　それをピッチで出すだけだ！
We'll defeat Osaka. Let's go!
大阪倒すぞ！
行くぞ！
Yeah!
Very good, that's the spirit. Don't let them outrun you!
よっしゃ
行こうぜ　行こうぜ！
走り負けんなよ　お前ら！
Just you watch.
見てろってんだ
I'm going to snap your stuck-up nose in the next 90 minutes, Dulfer.
この９０分で
その　デカッ鼻へし折ってやるよ…ダルファー
You've got find the way to believe
carry on and carry on
Carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
I'll say “never look back”
I'll say 「never look back」
oikaze o matte
追い風を待って
Wait for the tailwind
sou chance o nogasunara
そう chance を逃すなら
And if you missed the chance
そうchanceをのがすなら
自分が風になれ no fears no tears
jibun ga kaze ni nare
自分が風になれ
Become the wind yourself
no tears,Yes Let it go！
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
Get tough! Get tough!
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
限界追い越せ
genkai oikose yuke
限界追い越せ行け
Surpass your limits and go!
行け キツイほど
kitsui hodo heart in red
キツイほど　heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
heart in red
Go on! Go on!
Go on！(Stay cool！）
Stay cool!
Go on！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
asu wa mienai dakara
あすは見えないだから
Because we can't see into the future
あすは見えない だから
It's time to go
It's time to go yamerarenai
It's time to go やめられない
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
やめられない
Get tough!
Get tough！Get tough！ Get tough！
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
共に乗り越えて 行け
tomo ni norikoete yuke
共に乗り越えて行け
Let's get through it together
見えるか It's daybreak there
mieruka It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
Go on! Go on!
Go on！(Stay cool！) Go on！(We'll go！)
Stay cool!
We'll go!
yosoku dekinai dakara
予測できないだから
The future is unpredictable
It's time to go
It's time to go tomerarenai
It's time to go 止められない
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
止められない
It's only a 20cm difference.
Katayama is coming!
Stop me if you can.
Teams on a winning streak do look different.
They're picking up where they left off during the last game.